Fernando Cabral F. Rosa

Santana de Parnaíba - SP - Brazil

Summary

I have more than 10 years of professional experience, mostly in support and systems administration positions, but also did a little bit of software development, primarily for automation.

Worked as the IT Infrastructure Coordinator at Dafiti Group, managing a team of 10 people responsible for keeping the systems for 3 e-commerces, that together, are listed in the top 15 e-commerce in Brazil as reported by Retail and Consume Brazilian Society (SBVC).

Today, I'm working as IT Infrastructure Manager at Stoodi, where I'm responsible for the whole platform's cloud infrastructure, maintaining the website uptime, CI/CD pipelines, tests environments, etc.

Since early age I developed an interest for technology, starting to study C and Java with 12 years old, and maintaining Linux machines for study and personal use since 15 years old.

Skills

DevOps AWS, Docker, Packer, Terraform, Jenkins, CircleCI

System Administration Linux, Nginx, Icinga, Newrelic, ELK, VictorOps, PagerDuty

System Architecture LAMP, PHP-FPM, uWSGI, Redis, RabbitMQ

Programming Shell Script, Python, PHP, Git Misc PCI-DSS, Performance Tuning

Languages Portuguese (mother tongue), English (fluent), Spanish (basic)

Experience _

Stoodi Ensino a Distância São Paulo - SP

IT INFRASTRUCTURE MANAGER

Mar. 2018 - Present

Stoodi is platform for distance learning, focused in the ENEM exam, and as IT Manager:

- I'm responsible for the production and tests AWS environments' infrastructure.
- Member of Information security commitee.
- Migrated the version control system from Mercurial to Git.
- Migrated all webservers from Apache to Nginx.
- Implemented CI/CD workflows with CircleCI using Ansible, Terraform and Packer.
- Replaced Newrelic with an in-house stack using the Elastic Stack (Elasticsearch, Kibana, Filebeat, Metricbeat and Heartbeat).

São Paulo - SP

IT INFRASTRUCTURE COORDINATOR

Jan. 2016 - Mar. 2018

Global Fashion Group (GFG) is a group formed by Rocket Internet and other investors, consisting of major fashion e-commerces around the world, in Brazil represented by Dafiti, Kanui and Tricae. Working as an IT

- I was responsible for the infrastructure team, that maintained production and test environments.
- Merged Kanui and Tricae's infrastructure into Dafiti's, migrating both stacks from AWS to colocation.
- Reduced incidents, and time to solve them, by automating and documenting solutions.
- Implemented cache at CDN level for the Dafiti's mobile public API.
- Negotiate with vendors and partners, such as Akamai, AWS, Level3.
- Designed and delivered 4 new services as first steps towards a microservice architecture.
- Responsible for approvals regarding infrastructure changes, like firewall rules, to keep the environment PCI-DSS compliant.

Kanui Comércio Varejista

São Paulo - SP

Jul. 2014 - Jan. 2016

LEAD SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Before being merged with Dafiti, Kanui had its own infrastructure and there:

• I was responsible for the e-commerce migration from colocation to cloud, hosted on AWS, and its management making use of reserved and spot instances where available and auto scaling in order to make the infrastructure more cost effective.

- Along with the CTO, talked with vendors and partners for new services, support and best practices.
- Developed internal tools and a dashboard to automate development instances, so developers could launch and terminate their own instances without compromising security.

Kanui Comércio Vareiista

São Paulo - SP

Jul. 2014 - Jan. 2016

LEAD SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Rocket Internet is a German company that creates and invests in several startups, in its office in São Paulo I was member of the infrastructure team, where:

- I was responsible for the e-commerce migration from colocation to cloud, hosted on AWS, and its management making use of reserved and spot instances where available and auto scaling in order to make the infrastructure more cost effective.
- Along with the CTO, talked with vendors and partners for new services, support and best practices.
- Developed internal tools and a dashboard to automate development instances, so developers could launch and terminate their own instances without compromising security.

Orolix Desenvolvimento de Software

São Paulo - SP

System Administrator

Nov. 2007 - Aug. 2011 Orolix was a dial-up internet provider in São Paulo, in which the user would receive back some of the money

they spent while connected. Working there: • Kept the infrastructure running in a colocation, monitoring power usage, and hardware parts in general.

- Managed webservers and application servers for the website, and the Radius services used for users' authentication.
- Helped with the migration from all servers in bare metal to virtualization with Xen.
- Migrated all users accounts to Zimbra Collaboration Suite.

Intec Telecom System

São Paulo - SP Apr. 2007 - Nov. 2007

Intec Telecom Systems is a provider of Business Support System (BSS) software and related services for the telecommunications industry, having clients all around the world, some of them between world's top 100 telecom companies. As a trainee:

• Implemented an interconnection billing system for a client in Chile.

- Developed a C application to improve the performance of a mediation system for a client in Jamaica.
- Studied interconnection and activation systems.

Grupo InterCompany

São Paulo - SP

May 2006 - Apr. 2007

Grupo InterCompany is a company that develops solutions and products for IT infrastructure, and IBM Gold Business Partner. There I did:

- Linux support on-site and over the phone.
- IBM i5 OS and AS400 support over the phone.

Education _

Universidade Anhembi Morumbi

São Paulo - SP - Brazil

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2006 - 2011

4Linux

São Paulo - SP - Brazil

INFORMATION SECURITY, ENTREPRENEURSHIP AND ETHICS.

2005 - 2006